

LUCAS ASSIS RODRIGUES

COMPUTER ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a computer engineering graduate enthusiastic about building gadgets and sharing knowledge. So I worked mentoring software engineering students, also did research with embedded systems. Currently taking the Master program at the Apple Developer Academy improving my mobile skills.

EDUCATION

Universidade Federal de Itajubá

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering Graduated in Dec 2016

The University of Texas at El Paso

Study Abroad, Electrical and Computer Engineering Aug 2015 - May 2016

Apple Developer Academy

Master Class Expected graduation Jun 2018

CONTACT

lucasassisro.github.io lucas.assis.ro@gmail.com +39 340 584 4170 | +55 35 98866 7871

AWARDS

- Second place overall at HackCU 2016 for B-Note.
- WWDC 2018 scholarship for ColorPiano playground.

SKILLS

- Java - VHDL - Android - C# - MSP430 - Hibernate - Swift - Arduino - Git - C/C++ - Particle Photon - Sketch

EXPERIENCE

Universidade Federal de Itajubá

Teaching Assistant | Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

- Contributed to the strategic plan for software development.
- Worked with a team to design and develop a module for the university portal website.
- The API used for the website was Java Server Faces (JSF) communicating to a PostgreSQL database using Hibernate.

Universidade Federal de Itajubá

IT Intern | Aug 2014 - Mar 2015

- Worked with students on one-by-one interactions and groups to help with assignments, reinforce the course concepts, and improve their overall performance.
- Assisted with grading and documenting the performance of the classes.
- Assisted the professor with the following courses: Object-Oriented Programming (C++), Applied Programming (Java).

The University of Toledo

Research Intern | May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Worked to test, bug fix and improve the existing functionalities of an existing structural analysis software.
- Designed and developed new features.
- Coded in C++ using the MVC and OpenGL frameworks.

eWorld

Freelance Web Developer | Feb 2017 - Mar 2017

- Worked in both front-end and back-end development for the services provided by the company.
- Implemented the front-end functionalities in C# using ASP.NET MVC and Razor.
- Also implemented the back-end in C# using the Entity Framework to access the database.